AFROKK KHAN

pronounced af • rock

(437) 983-6721 | hi@afrokk.dev | LinkedIn.com/in/afrasiyab-k | GitHub.com/Afrokk | www.afrokk.dev

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineering grad with a parallel 7-year tech & creative design industry journey, managing a **1.7M subs YT** channel, former founder of a tech news website, and an avid freelancer with works featured in Forbes, Uber, and more.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL (Postgres/MySQL), Mongo, HTML/CSS, SASS **Frameworks**: React, Node.js/Bun, Flask, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt, Express.js, Prisma, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Tools: Git, Docker, REST APIs, CI/CD, Kubernetes, Prometheus, Adobe Suite, Figma, Unit Testing (Jest/Vitest/Pytest)

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

April 2024 – Present

McGill University

Montreal, QC – Full-time

- Full-Stack Developer for CHIME/FRB team at McGill, building and maintaining web-based tools and infrastructure for astrophysical data analysis and maintaining a high-performance computing cluster.
- Led migration of critical applications from React 16, CRA & Node to React 18, Vite & Bun, improving speeds by more than 2x and enhancing scalability & developer experience across the entire codebase.
- Maintaining data processing pipelines handling over 1.5 petabytes of extra-galactic data, utilizing Docker Swarm clusters, Prometheus/Grafana, Ansible, & more to support real-time data processing and infrastructure monitoring.

Creative Design Manager

March 2019 - Present

YouTube (@xeetechcare)

- Directing a thriving 1.7 million subscribers YouTube channel to produce tech content for a worldwide audience.
- Managing partnerships with top-tier brands including Samsung, Google, Chevrolet, and more across diverse sectors.
- Generating over **5 million monthly views** by producing **2,000+** videos on emerging tech, spanning **smartphones**, **computers**, **electric vehicles**, and more.
- Engineered a VueJS channel website and an interactive Discord Python chatbot to boost community engagement.
- Enhanced views from high CPM regions by 40% through SEO strategies, significantly boosting monetization potential.

Co-founder May 2016 – February 2019

GeeksULTD

• Established and piloted GeeksULTD.COM, a technology/gaming-based website for 3+ years.

- Achieved 2x faster load times by optimizing JavaScript & CSS and integrating CDN technologies like Cloudflare.
- Authored 550+ articles and reviews related to computers, technology, and gaming, reaching 100K+ monthly viewers.
- Partnered with Samsung, Logitech, MSi, and more to publish 30+ product reviews and editorials.

EDUCATION

University of Windsor

Windsor, ON

Bachelors in Computer Science, Minor in Communications, Media & Film | GPA: 3.9/4.0 | President's List

December 2023

PERSONAL PROJECTS (MORE ON AFROKK.DEV)

xeetechcare.com | Vue.js, Nuxt, SSR, Three.js, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, GSAP | GitHub

January 2024

- Pioneered xeetechcare.com, a bespoke server-side rendered website using Nuxt 3 (Vue.js).
- Boosted user time-on-site by **40%** through **real-time** timeline updates, integrating **APIs** from **YouTube**, **Twitter**, **Instagram**, and **TikTok**.
- Optimized data fetching pipelines with serverless functions and enhanced UX using Three.js and GSAP animations.

litmus.tools | TypeScript, React, SASS, WebAssembly, JavaScript, Vercel | GitHub

January 2023

- Engineered a comprehensive, **geography-specific** tax calculator and budgeting tool, utilizing **TypeScript**, **WebAssembly**, and **React** in a visually appealing interface.
- Incorporated data from the **US National Bureau of Economic Research** to offer **precise**, **ZIP code-specific** calculations and insights on users' savings and earnings.